<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Joey Shi - Software Developer</title>
    <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Joey Shi - Software Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 23:30:29 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Panning and zooming</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/panning_and_zooming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 23:30:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/panning_and_zooming/</guid>
      <description>This post will describe how panning and zooming can be implemented in an application.&#xA;Points can be described in world space or screen space. The world space is a linear basis that describes where objects in the world are positioned while the screen space is a basis that is used to describe points relative to the screen that the world is being drawn over.&#xA;When panning or zooming on the screen, a different translation and scale is being applied to the screen coordinates to determine how and what slice of the world should be drawn on the screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon curve visualization</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/dragon_curve_visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 23:28:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/dragon_curve_visualization/</guid>
      <description>The dragon curve is awesome :).&#xA;Prev Next </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide to self-hosting</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/guide_to_self_hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 23:29:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/guide_to_self_hosting/</guid>
      <description>Self-hosting is a convenient skill to have for anyone: it allows you set up personal VPNs, cloud services, and more. As a developer, I find they&amp;rsquo;re useful for cheaply serving my web app projects over the internet. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing my workflow for serving web applications in this post.&#xA;Setting up the Host Machine We first choose our host machine: a computer that we want to use as our server. An easy choice to start off with is a Raspberry Pi, which is a single-board basic personal computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Linux on old laptops</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/installing_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 23:14:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/installing_linux/</guid>
      <description>I spent the past few days attempting to convert an old Aspire One mini laptop and Lenovo laptop into usable Linux servers. This post documents the troubleshooting steps I took for each system.&#xA;Aspire One The important things to note about this system is that it has a 32-bit architecture and an i686 processor. Some of the compatible distros I considered installing were Arch Linux, Debian, and Linux Mint.&#xA;During the installation process for Arch Linux and Debian, my network interface was not detected, which made it annoying to discover available networks to connect to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Fibonacci sequence to the real domain</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/extending_fibonacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:58:20 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/extending_fibonacci/</guid>
      <description>The Fibonacci sequence can be written out as $0, 1, 1, 2, 3,\dots$, where the following terms is defined by the sum of the 2 previous terms. Letting $f(n)$ denote the $n$-th term of the sequence, we can write this as $f(n+2) = f(n+1) + f(n)$ with initial values $f(0) = 0$ and $f(1) = 1$.&#xA;Finding a closed formula To find a closed formula for this sequence, we can use the classic Characteristic Root Technique from discrete mathematics.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
