<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joey Shi - Software Developer</title>
    <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joey Shi - Software Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 10:49:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joeyshi.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PC Builder</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/pc_builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 10:49:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/pc_builder/</guid>
      <description>Website for browsing and putting together PC builds.&#xA;Website Test user credentials: User: pcbuilder Password: pcbuilder Source code This is a fullstack web application that was made using a Javalin webserver, MariaDB database, and Angular frontend. The website is served by my Raspberry Pi at home. The Pi runs Nginx as a reverse proxy to forward requests to a docker container running the PC Builder webserver.&#xA;API Reference PUT /users Updates the current logged in user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panning and zooming</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/panning_and_zooming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 23:30:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/panning_and_zooming/</guid>
      <description>This post goes over some of the mathematics involved in panning and zooming in graphical applications.&#xA;Points can be described in world space or view space. The world space is a linear basis that describes where objects positioned relative to the world while the view space is a basis that is used to describe points relative to the view that the user sees.&#xA;When panning or zooming in the view, a different translation and scale is being applied to view coordinates to determine what slice of the world should be drawn in the view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three.js Gallery</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/threejs_gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 12:49:16 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/threejs_gallery/</guid>
      <description>In the past week and a half, I&amp;rsquo;ve invested some time learning rigging and animation inside Blender. I&amp;rsquo;ve published some of the scenes I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a separate website, where I used three.js to render everything.&#xA;Website Source code Custom emotes Lethal Company - Doug Walker meme I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded a video render of this scene on Youtube here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide to self-hosting</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/guide_to_self_hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 23:29:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/guide_to_self_hosting/</guid>
      <description>Self-hosting is a convenient skill to have for anyone: it allows you set up personal VPNs, cloud services, and more. As a developer, I find they&amp;rsquo;re useful for cheaply serving my web app projects over the internet. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing my workflow for serving web applications in this post.&#xA;Setting up the Host Machine We first choose our host machine: a computer that we want to use as our server. An easy choice to start off with is a Raspberry Pi, which is a single-board basic personal computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Linux on old laptops</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/installing_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 23:14:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/installing_linux/</guid>
      <description>I spent the past few days attempting to convert an old Aspire One mini laptop and Lenovo laptop into usable Linux servers. This post documents the troubleshooting steps I took for each system.&#xA;Aspire One The important things to note about this system is that it has a 32-bit architecture and an i686 processor. Some of the compatible distros I considered installing were Arch Linux, Debian, and Linux Mint.&#xA;During the installation process for Arch Linux and Debian, my network interface was not detected, which made it annoying to discover available networks to connect to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devtools</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/devtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 19:19:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/devtools/</guid>
      <description>A collection of custom-made tools for programming tasks or challenges I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered.&#xA;Website Source code Webhook tester The webhook tester page allows users to capture requests sent to /webhook/&amp;lt;webhook_id&amp;gt;/capture and displays the contents. This feature was inspired by a cross-site scripting CTF challenge I attempted. This tool is useful for inspecting request contents from webhook service providers, such as Discord or Github.&#xA;DNS visualizer A DNS lookup visualization tool for tracing the search path for an iterative query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cool Wiki</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/cool_wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 10:49:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/cool_wiki/</guid>
      <description>In my final year at UBC, I decided to typeset notes for some of my courses.&#xA;Website Source code To make some of these notes publicly available, I used the following workflow to convert a collection of markdown notes into HTML pages using Pandoc.&#xA;Organization 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differential Equation Solver</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/diff_eq_solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 10:49:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/diff_eq_solver/</guid>
      <description>A desktop application that uses the finite difference method to solve differential equations.&#xA;PyPI Page Source code This application uses techniques from these lecture notes to compute the solution of PDEs numerically.&#xA;Numerical algorithm for solving the heat equation We let $u(t, x)$ be the solution function for the differential equation defined by&#xA;$$ \begin{align} \text{PDE}:\quad &amp;amp;u_{t}(t, x) = \alpha u_{xx}(t, x) + S(t, x), 0 &amp;lt; x \leq L, 0 &amp;lt; t \leq T \\ \text{BC}:\quad &amp;amp;u(t, 0) = \Phi_1(t),\quad u_{t}(t, L) = \Phi_2(t) \\ \text{IC}:\quad &amp;amp;u(0, x) = f(x) \end{align} $$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joey&#39;s Games</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/joey_games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 10:49:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/joey_games/</guid>
      <description>A collection of web games I made and host.&#xA;Game Website Platform Party - A real-time multiplayer 2D platformer. Snake - The classic snake game with a high-score board. Source code These games were made primarily using TypeScript and the HTML5 canvas API.&#xA;Image processing The first API I leveraged was the canvas scripting API, which offered useful image processing functions. To start using this feature, I added a canvas element in my main HTML template file</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Tech Salaries</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/visualizing_tech_salaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 10:49:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/projects/visualizing_tech_salaries/</guid>
      <description>A visualization for understanding the distribution of salaries of workers in the tech industry. This project was something I worked on with a group while taking CPSC 447 at UBC.&#xA;Visualization Write-up Source code Data Dictionary The following data was processed from Salaries for Jobs in Data Science and Tech (removed):&#xA;Attribute Type Cardinality/Range company Categorical 1631 title Categorical 15 basesalary Quantitative [0, 1659870] yearsofexperience Quantitative [0, 69] yearsatcompany Quantitative [0, 69] location Categorical 1050 This dataset consists of tech salary information from North America recorded in the time between January 1st, 2019 and September 9th, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Fibonacci sequence to the real domain</title>
      <link>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/extending_fibonacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:58:20 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joeyshi.xyz/posts/extending_fibonacci/</guid>
      <description>The Fibonacci sequence can be written out as $0, 1, 1, 2, 3,\dots$, where the following terms is defined by the sum of the 2 previous terms. Letting $f(n)$ denote the $n$-th term of the sequence, we can write this as $f(n+2) = f(n+1) + f(n)$ with initial values $f(0) = 0$ and $f(1) = 1$.&#xA;Finding a closed formula To find a closed formula for this sequence, we can use the classic Characteristic Root Technique from discrete mathematics.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
